A Biethnic Child's Identity
(Questioner) Hello, I am a father of
a 5th grade and a 2nd grade boys.
Their mom is Japanese.
When they first study history in school.
Children learn
hostile view of the Japanese
I prepared myself as much as possible
and explained it to kids the best I could.
But, as they get older, they ask me
questions about their identities.
I would like to ask you how I should
answer them in this situation.
People who live abroad
often ask these kind of questions.
When a person lives or
studies abroad for a long time,
and returns to Korea, he can't speak
Korean as good as native Koreans.
And when he is in States, he can't speak
English as good as Americans.
He would say,
"I can't speak Korean good enough,
neither English"
He also think he is neither
a Korean nor an American.
But, he feels that way because
he compares his identity with others.
If someone who grew up in America
speaks better Korean
than people who live in Korea,
that makes all Koreans stupid. Right?
And if someone who was born in Korea
goes to America to study complain
about speaking English
not as good as native Americans
who were born there,
that makes all Americans stupid.
The fact is the person can't speak
like native Koreans
and can't speak as good as native
Americans, that makes sense, right?
A thought that he can't speak
Korean as good as Koreans,
and can't speak English
as good as Americans
comes from him comparing
his identity to others.
So, how should he make his own identity?
"Any American who can speak Korean
as good as I can, come forward."
"Any Korean who can speak English
"They can only speak one language
but I can speak two languages"
That's his identity
He has to find his own identity.
As such, children who are born in Korea
only understand the Korean perspective.
And children who are born in Japan
only understand the Japanese perspective.
Koreans know Dokdo Island only as Dokdo
Japanese know it only as Dakeshima
But, your children have
a Korean father and a Japanese mother,
and they know
Dokdo is Dakeshima.
The Korea Stait is called
the Tsushima Stait,
and the East Sea is called
the Japanese Sea.
They know both sides.
So it's a good thing, not a bad thing.
What we need to know is
how Koreans and Japanese understand
the same issues in different way
Just tell your children
it's nothing strange.
Nongae was a patriot to Koreans, right?
To Japanese, she was a suicide commando
(Kamikaze), right?
She was the first suicide commando.
She embrace the Japanese General
and jumped off the cliff. She killed
herself to kill someone else.
So, we see the situation in one way,
and they see it in another way.
So you can tell your children, "You have
insights since you understand both sides."
"It's good to see both sides."
"You have wisdom because of your insight.
Everything is OK." You can tell this to your kids
Why you worrying about this?
It's not that I am worried. I thought
I've explained it enough to them
But I wanted them to hear it
directly from you.
So I brought my kids here
Please take good care of your
health at the change of season.
(Sumin Laughter)